<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ruleset xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="warmachine.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <armies>
    <army faction="faction_everblight" name="Everblight">
      <warlocks>
        <warlock id="Ew01" name="Lylyth1" generation="P" generation_id="Lylyth" full_name="Lylyth, Herald of Everblight" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Warlock" fury="5" warbeast_points="6" fa="C" completed="true">
          <basestats name="LYLYTH" spd="7" str="4" mat="5" rat="7" def="16" arm="14" cmd="8" hitpoints="15" eyelesssight="true" pathfinder="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Hellsinger" rng="12" rof="2" aoe="-" pow="12" magical="true">
              <capacity title="BLOOD LURE">Warbeasts in this model's battlegroup can charge enemy models hit by this weapon this turn without being forced.</capacity>
              <capacity title="WITCH MARK">If this attack hits an enemy model during this model's activation, this model can target and automatically hit that model with spells, ignoring RNG and LOS, until the end of this model's activation.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
			<melee_weapon name="Bow Blade" pow="3" p_plus_s="7" />            
          </weapons>
          <feat title="Field of Slaughter">While in Lylyth's control area, friendly Faction models roll an additional die on attack rolls this turn.</feat>
          <spell name="BAD BLOOD" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="YES">A warlock leaching from target warbeast suffers 1 damage point for each fury leached. The affected warbeast cannot be healed or have damage transferred to it and loses Regeneration.</spell>
          <spell name="PARASITE" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="YES">Target model/unit suffers –3 ARM and this model gains +1 ARM.</spell>
          <spell name="ERUPTION OF SPINES" cost="3" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="10" up="NO" off="YES">If target model is hit, d6 nearest models within 5" of it suffer a POW 10 damage roll.</spell>
          <capacity title="BUSHWHACK">During its activation, this model can make its combat action before its normal movement. If it does, it must make a full advance as its normal movement this activation.</capacity>
        </warlock>
        <warlock id="Ex01" name="Lylyth2" generation="E" generation_id="Lylyth" full_name="Lylyth, Shadow of Everblight" qualification="Legion Epic Blighted Nyss Warlock" fury="5" warbeast_points="5" fa="C" completed="true">
          <basestats name="LYLYTH" spd="7" str="4" mat="5" rat="8" def="16" arm="14" cmd="8" hitpoints="15" eyelesssight="true" pathfinder="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Whisper" rng="12" rof="2" aoe="-" pow="12" magical="true" />
          </weapons>
          <feat title="Decimation">While in Lylyth's control area, friendly Faction models' ranged weapons gain Snipe. While in Lylyth's control area, models in her battlegroup can make one additional ranged attack during their activations. Attacks gained from Decimation do not count against a weapon's ROF. Decimation lasts for one turn. (Ranged weapons with Snipe gain +4 RNG).</feat>
          <spell name="PIN CUSHION" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="YES">Friendly Faction models gain an additional die on ranged attack and ranged attack damage rolls against target enemy model/unit. Discard the lowest die in each roll.</spell>
          <spell name="PURSUIT" cost="2" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="YES">If target enemy model/unit advances during its normal movement, immediately after ending this movement one model in this model's battlegroup that is in its control area can make a full advance.</spell>
          <spell name="SHADOW PACK" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Models in this model's battlegroup gain Stealth while in its control area.</spell>
          <capacity title="EVASIVE">This model cannot be targeted by free strikes. This model can advance up to 2" immediately after an enemy ranged attack that missed it is resolved unless it was missed while advancing.</capacity>
          <capacity title="RANGE AMPLIFIER">When this model casts a spell and is the point of origin for the spell, the spell gains +5 RNG.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SNAP FIRE">When this model destroys one or more enemy models with a ranged attack during its combat action, immediately after that attack is resolved this model can make one normal ranged attack. Attack gained from Snap Fire do not count against a weapon's ROF and cannot generate additional attacks from Snap Fire.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SWIFT HUNTER">When this model destroys an enemy model with a normal ranged attack, immediately after the attack is resolved it can advance up to 2".</capacity>
        </warlock>
        <warlock id="Ez01" name="Lylyth3" generation="EE" generation_id="Lylyth" full_name="Lylyth, Reckoning of Everblight" qualification="Legion Epic Blighted Nyss Cavalry Warlock" fury="5" warbeast_points="5" fa="C" completed="true">
          <basestats name="LYLYTH" spd="9" str="8" mat="6" rat="8" def="14" arm="16" cmd="8" hitpoints="18" eyelesssight="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Whisper" rng="12" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="12" magical="true">
              <capacity title="BLOOD BOON">Once per activation, immediately after resolving an attack in which it destroyed a living enemy model with this weapon, this model can cast a spell with COST 3 or less without spending fury.</capacity>
              <capacity title="AUTO FIRE [3]">Make 3 ranged attacks targeting a primary target and any number of secondary targets within 2" of the first target. Ignore intervening models when declaring secondary targets. A secondary target cannot be targeted by more attacks than the primary target. Auto Fire counts as one attack for ROF.</capacity>
              <capacity title="REAR ATTACK">When declaring and resolving attacks with this weapon, this model's front arc extends to 360 degrees.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
			<melee_weapon name="Scything Blade" pow="4" p_plus_s="12" location="L">
              <capacity title="THRESHING BLADES">This model can add this weapon's POW to its trample power attack damage rolls.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
            <melee_weapon name="Scything Blade" pow="4" p_plus_s="12" location="R">
              <capacity title="THRESHING BLADES">See above.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>            
            <mount_weapon name="Mount" pow="12" />
          </weapons>
          <feat title="The Reaping">When an enemy model is directly hit by a ranged attack made by a friendly Faction model while the friendly Faction model is in Lylyth's control area, the enemy model suffers Death Chill. The Reaping lasts for one turn. (A model suffering Death Chill must forfeit either its movement or action on its next activation.)</feat>
          <spell name="ESCORT" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Warbeasts in this model's battlegroup beginning their activations in its control area gain +2" movement. This model gains +2 ARM while one or more warbeasts in its battlegroup are within 3" of it.</spell>
          <spell name="FROST HAMMER" cost="2" rng="SP8" aoe="-" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES">Frost Hammer causes cold damage. On a critical hit, a model become stationary for one round unless it has Immunity: Cold.</spell>
          <spell name="WIND WALL" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">This model cannot make ranged attacks, and non-magical ranged attacks targeting it automatically miss. While completely within 3" of this model, models cannot make ranged attacks and non-magical ranged attacks targeting them automatically miss. Wind Wall lasts for one round.</spell>
          <capacity title="BATTLE ENGINE">This model is a battle engine and is not a warrior model.</capacity>
          <capacity title="POWER ATTACK TRAMPLE">This model can make trample power attacks.</capacity>
          <capacity title="WEAPON PLATFORM">This model can make melee and ranged attacks in the same activation. When this model makes its initial melee attacks or a power attack, it can also make its initial ranged attacks. This model can make ranged attacks even while in melee.</capacity>
        </warlock>
        <warlock id="Ew02" name="Thagrosh1" generation="P" full_name="Thagrosh, Prophet of Everblight" qualification="Legion Blighted Ogrun Warlock" fury="7" warbeast_points="5" fa="C" completed="true">
          <basestats name="THAGROSH" spd="5" str="9" mat="7" rat="5" def="14" arm="16" cmd="9" hitpoints="18" terror="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Blighted Breath" rng="SP8" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="12" fire="true" />
			<melee_weapon name="Rapture" pow="7" p_plus_s="16" magical="true" reach="true">
              <capacity title="ERUPTION OF ASH">If a model is boxed by an attack made with this weapon, center a 3" AOE cloud effect on the boxed model and then remove that model from play. The AOE remains in play for one round. Enemy models in the AOE when it was put in play are hit and suffer a POW 12 fire damage roll. Enemy models entering or ending their activation in the AOE suffer a POW 12 fire damage roll. Eruption of Ash damage rolls cannot be boosted.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
            <melee_weapon name="Claw" pow="3" p_plus_s="12" />            
          </weapons>
          <feat title="Dark Revival">Return one destroyed warbeast that was part of Thagrosh's battlegroup to play. Place it anywhere within 3" of him. The warbeast forfeits its action this turn.</feat>
          <spell name="BAD BLOOD" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="YES">A warlock leaching from target warbeast suffers 1 damage point for each fury leached. The affected warbeast cannot be healed or have damage transferred to it and loses Regeneration.</spell>
          <spell name="DRACONIC BLESSING" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly Faction model/unit gains +2 STR and Terror.</spell>
          <spell name="FOG OF WAR" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Models gain concealment while in this model's control area.</spell>
          <spell name="MUTAGENESIS" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES">Target model boxed by Mutagenesis is removed from play. When Mutagenesis boxes an enemy model and this model was the spell's point of origin, this model can replace the boxed model when it is removed from play. This model cannot advance this activation after replacing another model as a result of Mutagenesis. Mutagenesis can be cast only once per activation.</spell>
          <spell name="OBLITERATION" cost="4" rng="10" aoe="4" pow="15" up="NO" off="YES">The force of this attack blasts apart the earth itself.</spell>
          <capacity title="DEATH SHROUD">While within this model's command range, enemy models suffer –2 STR.</capacity>
          <capacity title="ATHANC">Immediately after leaching, this model gains 1 fury point if it has fewer fury points than its FURY.</capacity>
          <capacity title="ATTUNED SPIRIT [LEGION]">Once per activation, this model can cast the animus of a Legion warbeast in its battlegroup as a spell without spending fury.</capacity>
        </warlock>
        <warlock id="Ex02" name="Thagrosh2" generation="E" full_name="Thagrosh, the Messiah" qualification="Legion Epic Blighted Ogrun Warlock" fury="7" warbeast_points="3" fa="C" completed="true">
          <basestats name="THAGROSH" spd="5" str="11" mat="7" rat="5" def="13" arm="17" cmd="10" hitpoints="20" abomination="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Blight Fire" rng="SP10" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="12" fire="true" frost="true" continuous_fire="true">
              <capacity title="CRITICAL FREEZE">On a critical hit, the model hit becomes stationary for one round unless it has Immunity: Cold.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
			<melee_weapon name="Rapture" pow="7" p_plus_s="18" magical="true" reach="true">
              <capacity title="ERUPTION OF ASH">If a model is boxed by an attack made with this weapon, center a 3" AOE cloud effect on the boxed model and then remove that model from play. The AOE remains in play for one round. Enemy models in the AOE when it was put in play are hit and suffer a POW 12 fire damage roll. Enemy models entering or ending their activation in the AOE suffer a POW 12 fire damage roll. Eruption of Ash damage rolls cannot be boosted.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
            <melee_weapon name="Claw" pow="3" p_plus_s="12" />            
          </weapons>
          <feat title="Dragon Storm">After all friendly models have completed their activations this turn, each warbeast in Thagrosh's battlegroup that is in his control area can make a full advance followed by one normal melee attack. Completely resolve each model's movement and attack before moving on to the next model.</feat>
          <spell name="DRAGON'S BLOOD" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly non-warlock Faction model/unit gains +2 ARM. When an affected model is disabled by a melee attack, roll a d6. On a roll of 5 or 6, the attacker suffers 1 damage point.</spell>
          <spell name="FLESH EATER" cost="3" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="13" up="NO" off="YES">When a living enemy model is boxed by Flesh Eater, it is removed from play and this model or a living warbeast in its battlegroup in its control area heals d3 damage points.</spell>
          <spell name="MANIFEST DESTINY" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">While in this model's control area, models in its battlegroup gain an additional die on melee attack and melee damage rolls this turn. Discard the lowest die of each roll.</spell>
          <spell name="SCOURGE" cost="4" rng="8" aoe="3" pow="13" up="NO" off="YES">Models hit by Scourge are knocked down.</spell>
          <spell name="UNNATURAL AGGRESSION" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">If target friendly non-trooper Faction model suffered damage during your opponent's last turn, during your next Maintenance Phase it can make a full advance. During this movement, it must move toward the nearest enemy model.</spell>
          <capacity title="ATHANC">Immediately after leaching, this model gains 1 fury point if it has fewer fury points than its FURY.</capacity>
          <capacity title="BLOOD SPAWN">Once per game, when this model suffers 5 or more damage points from an enemy attack that are not transferred, after the attack is resolved you can place a non-character Faction lesser warbeast in play anywhere completely within 3" of this model. The warbeast is part of this model's battlegroup. The warbeast cannot activate this turn.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
        </warlock>
        <warlock id="Ew03" name="Vayl1" generation="P" full_name="Vayl, Disciple of Everblight" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Warlock" fury="8" warbeast_points="6" fa="C" completed="true">
          <basestats name="VAYL" spd="6" str="5" mat="3" rat="6" def="15" arm="13" cmd="9" hitpoints="14" immunity_frost="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Oraculus" rng="8" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="8" magical="true">
              <capacity title="GUIDED">Attacks made with this weapon automatically hit.</capacity>
              <capacity title="SPELLBOUND">This model can channel spells through a model hit by an attack made with this weapon. Spellbound lasts for one turn.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <feat title="Cat &amp; Mouse">At the end of this turn after all friendly models have ended their activations, one friendly Faction model in Vayl's control area can make a full advance for each enemy model in her control area at that time. During this movement, the affected model cannot be targeted by free strikes. A model can advance only once per turn as a result of Cat &amp; Mouse.</feat>
          <spell name="CHILLER" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">While within 2" of target friendly Faction model/unit, enemy models suffer –2 DEF unless they have Immunity: Cold.</spell>
          <spell name="HOARFROST" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="3" pow="14" up="NO" off="YES">Hoarfrost causes cold damage. On a critical hit, models in the AOE become stationary for one round unless they have Immunity: Cold.</spell>
          <spell name="INCITE" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Models in this model's battlegroup gain +2 to attack and damage rolls against enemy models while the enemy model's are in this model's command range. Incite lasts for one turn.</spell>
          <spell name="LEASH" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Immediately after this model ends its normal movement, target warbeast in its battlegroup can advance up to 3" toward it.</spell>
          <spell name="MALICE" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="10" up="NO" off="YES">Add +1 to the damage roll for each fury point on the target model.</spell>
          <spell name="RAMPAGER" cost="3" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="YES">Take control of target enemy non-character warbeast. You can make one full advance with the warbeast and can then make one normal attack with it, then Rampager expires. While the warbeast is affected by Rampager, it cannot be forced and you cannot use its animus. Rampager can be cast only once per turn.</spell>
          <capacity title="DARK SENTINEL">Once per turn, when an enemy model ends its normal movement within 5" of this model, a friendly Faction warbeast within 5" of this model can immediately make a full advance followed by a normal melee or ranged attack targeting the enemy model. The warbeast gains boosted attack and damage rolls against the enemy model.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SNOW-WREATHED">This model always has concealment.</capacity>
          <capacity title="TALION">Once per turn when this model suffers damage from an enemy attack, it can spend 1 fury point to transfer half the damage to an enemy warbeast in its control area but must suffer the rest of the damage itself.</capacity>
        </warlock>
        <warlock id="Ex03" name="Vayl2" generation="E" full_name="Vayl, Consul of Everblight" qualification="Legion Epic Blighted Nyss Warlock" fury="8" warbeast_points="6" fa="C" completed="true">
          <basestats name="VAYL" spd="6" str="5" mat="3" rat="7" def="15" arm="14" cmd="9" hitpoints="14" gunfighter="true" immunity_frost="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Oraculi" rng="10" rof="3" aoe="-" pow="8" magical="true">
              <capacity title="SPELLBOUND">This model can channel spells through a model hit by an attack made with this weapon. Spellbound lasts for one turn.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <feat title="Dark Miracles">This activation Vayl can cast each of the spells on her card once without spending fury points.</feat>
          <spell name="ADMONITION" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">When an enemy model advances and ends its movement within 6" of target model in this model’s battlegroup, the affected model can immediately advance up to 3", then Admonition expires. The affected model cannot be targeted by free strikes during this movement.</spell>
          <spell name="ICY GRIP" cost="2" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="YES">Target enemy warrior model/unit without Immunity: Cold suffers –2 DEF and cannot run or make special attacks.</spell>
          <spell name="OBLITERATION" cost="4" rng="10" aoe="4" pow="15" up="NO" off="YES">The force of this attack blasts apart the earth itself.</spell>
          <spell name="OCCULTATION" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model/unit gains Stealth.</spell>
          <spell name="PURIFICATION" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Continuous effects, animi, and upkeep spells in this model's control area immediately expire.</spell>
          <spell name="REFUGE" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">When target friendly Faction model hits an enemy model with an attack during its activation, immediately after its combat action ends the affected model can make a full advance. It cannot be targeted by free strikes during this movement.</spell>
          <capacity title="QUICK DRAW">Once during your opponent's turn, when an enemy model within 10" of this model that is in its LOS targets this model with a ranged attack, this model can make a ranged attack against the enemy model before it makes its attack roll. If this model's ranged attack hits, the enemy model suffers no damage but its attack automatically misses.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SERENITY">At the beginning of your Control Phase, before leaching, you can remove 1 fury point from a friendly Faction warbeast within 1" of this model.</capacity>
        </warlock>
        <warlock id="EW04" name="Rhyas, Sigil of Everblight" generation="P" full_name="Rhyas, Sigil of Everblight" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Warlock" fury="5" warbeast_points="6" fa="C" completed="true">
          <basestats name="RHYAS" spd="7" str="5" mat="8" rat="6" def="16" arm="14" cmd="8" hitpoints="16" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Antiphon" pow="7" p_plus_s="12" magical="true" reach="true" weapon_master="true">
              <capacity title="CRITICAL DECAPITATION">On a critical hit, double the damage exceeding the ARM of the model hit. A model disabled by this attack cannot make a Tough roll.</capacity>
              <capacity title="SPIRIT EATER">This model can reave fury points from enemy warbeasts destroyed by this weapon. Other models cannot reave fury points from enemy warbeasts destroyed by this weapon.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <feat title="Tide of Blood">Rhyas and friendly Legion models activating in her control area gain one additional melee attack during their activations. The first time a friendly Legion model damages an enemy model with a melee attack during its activation while in Rhyas' control area, immediately place the attacking model anywhere B2B with the damaged model. Tide of Blood lasts for one turn.</feat>
          <spell name="DASH" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">While in this model's control area, friendly Faction warrior models cannot be targeted by free strikes. This model and friendly Faction warrior models activating in its control area gain +1 SPD. Dash lasts for one turn.</spell>
          <spell name="OCCULTATION" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model/unit gains Stealth.</spell>
          <spell name="RAPPORT" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target warbeast in this model's battlegroup can use this model's current MAT and RAT in place of its own. This model can transfer damage to the warbeast even if it is not in this model's control area. This model can transfer damage to the warbeast once per turn without spending fury.</spell>
          <capacity title="ACROBATICS">This model can advance through other models if it has enough movement to move completely past their bases. This model cannot be targeted by free strikes. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="PERFECT BALANCE">This model cannot be targeted by combined melee attacks, combined ranged attacks, or free strikes. Models do not gain back strike bonuses against this model. When knocked down, this model can stand up during its activation without forfeiting its movement or action if it is able to forfeit its movement or action to stand up.</capacity>
          <capacity title="CHANNELER [SAERYN]">While this model is not in melee and is in Saeryn's control area, Saeryn can channel spells through it.</capacity>
          <capacity title="RIPOSTE">When this model is missed by an enemy melee attack, immediately after the attack is resolved it can make one normal melee attack against the attacking model.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SPRINT">At the end of this model's activation, if it destroyed one or more enemy models with melee attacks this activation it can make a full advance.</capacity>
        </warlock>
        <warlock id="EW05" name="Saeryn, Omen of Everblight" generation="P" full_name="Saeryn, Omen of Everblight" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Warlock" fury="7" warbeast_points="5" fa="C" completed="true">
          <basestats name="SAERYN" spd="7" str="5" mat="6" rat="7" def="16" arm="14" cmd="8" hitpoints="16" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Thrown Deathspur" rng="7" rof="3" aoe="-" pow="3" magical="true">
              <capacity title="GRIEVOUS WOUNDS">When a model is hit by this weapon, for one round it loses Tough, cannot heal or be healed, and cannot transfer damage.</capacity>
              <capacity title="THROWN">Add this model's STR to the POW of this ranged attack.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
			<melee_weapon name="Deathspur" pow="3" p_plus_s="8" magical="true">
              <capacity title="GRIEVOUS WOUNDS">See above.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>            
          </weapons>
          <feat title="Foreboding">While within her control area, small-, medium-, and large-based models in Saeryn’s battlegroup cannot be targeted by melee attacks for one round.</feat>
          <spell name="BANISHING WARD" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Enemy upkeep spells on target friendly model/unit expire. Affected models cannot be targeted by enemy spells or animi.</spell>
          <spell name="BLIGHT BRINGER" cost="4" rng="10" aoe="5" pow="12" up="NO" off="NO">Center a 5" AOE on target friendly Faction warbeast. Enemy models in the AOE when it is put in play are hit and suffer a POW 12 corrosion damage roll. An enemy model or friendly non-Faction model entering or ending its activation in the AOE suffers 1 of corrosion damage. Blight Bringer lasts for one round.</spell>
          <spell name="BREATH STEALER" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="YES">Target model/unit suffers –2 SPD and DEF for one round. Breath Stealer can be cast only once per turn.</spell>
          <spell name="HELLFIRE" cost="3" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="14" up="NO" off="YES">A model/unit hit by Hellfire must pass a command check or flee.</spell>
          <spell name="RESPAWN" cost="3" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">When target warbeast in this model's battlegroup is disabled by an enemy attack anytime except while it is advancing, place it anywhere within 3" of its current location. It heals 1 damage point in each aspect, then Respawn expires.</spell>
          <capacity title="FORCE BARRIER">This model gains +2 DEF against ranged attack rolls and does not suffer blast damage.</capacity>
          <capacity title="CHANNELER [RHYAS]">While this model is not engaged and is in Rhyas's control area, Rhyas can channel spells through it.</capacity>
        </warlock>
        <warlock id="EW06" name="Absylonia1" generation="P" full_name="Absylonia, Terror of Everblight" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Warlock" fury="6" warbeast_points="5" fa="C" completed="true">
          <basestats name="ABSYLONIA" spd="7" str="7" mat="7" rat="6" def="16" arm="14" cmd="8" hitpoints="16" abomination="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Blight Claw " pow="6" count="2" p_plus_s="13" magical="true">
              <capacity title="CRITICAL GRIEVOUS WOUNDS">On a critical hit, the model hit by this weapon loses Tough, cannot heal or be healed, and cannot transfer damage for one round.</capacity>
              <capacity title="SPIRIT EATER">This model can reave fury points from enemy warbeasts destroyed by this weapon. Other models cannot reave fury points from enemy warbeasts destroyed by this weapon.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <feat title="Panacea">Remove all damage from Absylonia. She can then suffer 1 or more damage points. For each damage point she suffers, remove all damage from one warbeast in her battlegroup in her control area.</feat>
          <spell name="BLIGHT FIELD" cost="2" rng="CTRL" aoe="4" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Place the 4" AOE anywhere completely in this model's control area. While in the AOE, enemy models cannot be used to channel spells, be forced, or be allocated focus. The AOE remains in play for one round. Blight Field can be cast once per round.</spell>
          <spell name="CARNIVORE" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model/unit gains +2 to melee attack rolls against living models. When an affected model boxes a living model with a melee attack, the boxed model is removed from play and this model heals d3 damage points.</spell>
          <spell name="FORCED EVOLUTION" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly living Faction warbeast gains +2 STR and DEF.</spell>
          <spell name="PLAYING GOD" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target warbeast in this model's battlegroup can make power attack without being forced and gains Terror. Its melee weapons gain Open Fist and Reach.</spell>
          <capacity title="RESOURCEFUL">This model can upkeep spells on models in its battlegroup without spending fury.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SPONTANEOUS MUTATION">This model can spend fury points during its activation to spontaneously mutate. For each fury point spent it gains one of the following abilities for one turn.</capacity>
          <capacity title="● BARBED HOOKS">This model's melee weapons gain Reach.</capacity>
          <capacity title="● FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="● WARP STRENGTH">This model gains +2 STR.</capacity>
        </warlock>
        <warlock id="Ex06" name="Absylonia2" generation="E" full_name="Absylonia, Daughter of Everblight" qualification="Legion Epic Blighted Nyss Warlock" fury="6" warbeast_points="5" fa="C" completed="true">
          <basestats name="ABSYLONIA" spd="7" str="8" mat="7" rat="6" def="15" arm="16" cmd="8" hitpoints="18" abomination="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Claw " pow="6" count="2" p_plus_s="14" magical="true" />
            <melee_weapon name="Stinger" pow="4" p_plus_s="12" magical="true">
              <capacity title="ENERGY SIPHON">When this attack hits an enemy model with 1 or more focus or fury points on it, that model loses 1 focus or fury point and this model gains 1 fury point.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <feat title="Metamorphose">Models in Absylonia's battlegroup that are currently in her control area gain +2 STR and Flight, and their melee weapons gain Reach. Metamorphose lasts for one round.</feat>
          <spell name="FORTIFY" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target warbeast in this model's battlegroup gains +2 ARM. The affected model and any friendly model B2B with it cannot be knocked down, pushed, or moved by a slam.</spell>
          <spell name="PSYCHO SUGERY" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Each model in this model's battlegroup currently in its control area immediately heals d3+1 damage points. This spell can only be cast once per turn.</spell>
          <spell name="RETURN FIRE" cost="1" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">When target friendly Faction model is targeted by an enemy ranged attack, after the attack is resolved the affected model can make one normal melee or ranged attack, then Return Fire expires. Return Fire lasts for one round.</spell>
          <spell name="TELEPORT" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Place this model anywhere completely within 8" of its current location, then its activation ends.</spell>
          <capacity title="CONFERRED RAGE">Warbeasts in this model's battlegroup beginning their activations in its control area can charge or make power attacks without being forced. When this model destroys one or more enemy models during its activation, warbeasts in its battlegroup beginning their activations in its control area gain +2 SPD and MAT for one turn.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
        </warlock>
        <warlock id="EW07" name="Bethayne, Voice of Everblight &amp; Belphagor" generation="E" full_name="Bethayne, Voice of Everblight &amp; Belphagor" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Warlock" fury="7" warbeast_points="3" fa="C" companionId="EB20" completed="true">
          <basestats name="BETHAYNE" spd="6" str="5" mat="6" rat="4" def="16" arm="12" cmd="9" hitpoints="14" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Talons of Everblight" pow="5" count="2" p_plus_s="10" magical="true" continuous_corrosion="true" />
          </weapons>
          <feat title="Litany of Everblight">While in this model's control area, friendly Faction models gain boosted magic attack rolls and magic damage rolls, and friendly Faction warbeasts can use their animi without being forced. Litany of Everblight lasts for one turn.</feat>
          <spell name="ASHEN VEIL" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model/unit gains concealment. Living enemy models suffer –2 to attack rolls while within 2" of an affected model.</spell>
          <spell name="BLOOD THORN" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model/unit's ranged and melee weapons gain the Corrosion continuous effect.</spell>
          <spell name="CARNIVORE" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model/unit gains +2 to melee attack rolls against living models. When an affected model boxes a living model with a melee attack, the boxed model is removed from play and this model heals d3 damage points.</spell>
          <spell name="ERUPTION OF SPINES" cost="3" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="10" up="NO" off="YES">If target model is hit, d6 nearest models within 5" of it suffer a POW 10 damage roll.</spell>
          <spell name="GALLOWS" cost="3" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="13" up="NO" off="YES">When an enemy model is hit by this attack, it can be pushed d6" directly toward Gallows' point of origin.</spell>
          <capacity title="FLESH MELD">This model can use Flesh Meld at any time during its activation while B2B with Belphagor in its battlegroup. Remove this model from the table. Belphagor becomes a warlock warrior model and loses Blood Creation and Soulless. Belphagor cannot activate after this model uses Flesh Meld during the turn it used Flesh Meld. While melded, Belphagor takes control of this model's battlegroup, its base CMD becomes 9, and its base FURY becomes 7. Any effects on this model when it melds are applied to Belphagor. Remove the fury points currently on Belphagor. If there are any fury points on this model when it melds, place them on Belphagor. While melded, Belphagor can cast this model's spells and use its feat, is not considered to be a warbeast, and loses its animus. While melded, Belphagor can make slam, throw, two-handed throw, headlock/weapon lock, and push power attacks without being forced. While melded, Belphagor suffers damage like a warbeast but does not suffer the effects of crippled aspects. Effects modifying the amount of damage to or the manner in which damage is applied to a warbeast also apply to Belphagor. This model can separate from Belphagor during your Maintenance Phase. If it does, place it B2B with Belphagor. If Belphagor is destroyed or removed from play while this model is melded with it, this model is destroyed. When Bethayne leaves the table, upkeep spells she cast do not immediately expire and warbeasts in her battlegroup do not go wild. While melded, Belphagor can upkeep spells cast by Bethayne. When Bethayne returns to play, she retains any damage she had suffered before leaving the table. Bethayne can upkeep spells cast by Belphagor.</capacity>
        </warlock>
        <warlock id="EW08" name="Kallus, Wrath of Everblight" generation="P" full_name="Kallus, Wrath of Everblight" qualification="Legion Warlock" fury="6" warbeast_points="5" fa="C" completed="true">
          <basestats name="KALLUS" spd="6" str="7" mat="7" rat="4" def="14" arm="16" cmd="8" hitpoints="18" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Hellbrand" pow="7" p_plus_s="14" magical="true" reach="true">
              <capacity title="FLAME BURST">When this model boxes an enemy model with this weapon, enemy models within 1" of the boxed model suffer the Fire continuous effect.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <feat title="Host of Angels">When a friendly living non-Incubus warrior model in Kallus' control area is disabled by an enemy attack, you can replace it with an Incubus model. The replaced model is removed from play. While in Kallus' control area friendly soulless warrior models gain +2 DEF. Host of Angels lasts for one round.</feat>
          <spell name="DARK GUIDANCE" cost="4" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">While in this model's control area, friendly Faction models gain an additional die on their melee attack rolls this turn.</spell>
          <spell name="ERUPTION" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="3" pow="14" up="NO" off="YES">Models hit suffer a POW 14 fire damage roll. The AOE is a cloud effect that remains in play for one round. Models entering or ending their activation in the AOE suffer an unboostable POW 14 fire damage roll.</spell>
          <spell name="FLASHING BLADE" cost="1" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">This model immediately makes one normal melee attack with one of its melee weapons against each enemy model in its LOS that is in the weapon's melee range. These attacks are simultaneous.</spell>
          <spell name="IGNITE" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model/unit gains +2 to melee attack damage rolls. Affected models gain Critical Fire on their normal melee attacks.</spell>
          <capacity title="HYPER REGENERATION">This model automatically heals d3 damage points at the start of each of its activations.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
          <capacity title="UNCONQUERABLE">While in this model's command range, friendly Faction warrior models gain Unyielding. (While engaging an enemy model, a model with Unyielding gains +2 ARM.)</capacity>
        </warlock>
      </warlocks>
      <warbeasts>
        <warbeast id="EB01" name="Harrier" full_name="Harrier" qualification="Legion Lesser Warbeast" fa="U" cost="2" fury="2" threshold="7" damage_spiral="4-4-5" completed="true">
          <basestats name="HARRIER" spd="7" str="6" mat="5" rat="3" def="14" arm="12" cmd="7" eyelesssight="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Talons" pow="4" p_plus_s="10" />
          </weapons>
          <animus name="TRUE STRIKE" cost="1" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">The next melee attack roll made by this model this activation hits automatically, then True Strike expires. A model can be affected by True Strike only once per turn.</animus>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="LESSER WARBEAST">This model cannot make power attacks.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SPRINT">At the end of this model's activation, if it destroyed one or more enemy models with melee attacks this activation it can make a full advance.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB02" name="Shredder" full_name="Shredder" qualification="Legion Lesser Warbeast" fa="U" cost="2" fury="2" threshold="7" damage_spiral="4-4-5" completed="true">
          <basestats name="SHREDDER" spd="6" str="6" mat="5" rat="3" def="13" arm="12" cmd="7" eyelesssight="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Bite" pow="4" p_plus_s="10" location="H" />
          </weapons>
          <animus name="TENACITY" cost="1" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Target friendly model gains +1 DEF and ARM. Tenacity lasts for one round.</animus>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="LESSER WARBEAST">This model cannot make power attacks.</capacity>
          <capacity title="RABID">This model can be forced during its activation to gain +2 SPD, Pathfinder, and boosted attack and damage rolls for one turn.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SNACKING">When this model boxes a living model with a melee attack, this model can heal d3 damage points. If this model heals, the boxed model is removed from play.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB03" name="Nephilim Protector" full_name="Nephilim Protector" qualification="Legion Light Warbeast" fa="U" cost="5" fury="3" threshold="10" damage_spiral="8-7-7" completed="true">
          <basestats name="PROTECTOR" spd="6" str="8" mat="5" rat="3" def="12" arm="18" cmd="8" eyelesssight="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Halberd" pow="4" p_plus_s="12" reach="true">
              <capacity title="SET DEFENSE">A model in this model's front arc suffers –2 on charge, slam power attack, and impact attack rolls against this model.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <animus name="SAFEGUARD" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Target friendly model cannot be knocked down. When it is slammed, reduce the slam distance rolled by 3. Safeguard lasts for one round.</animus>
          <capacity title="EMPHATIC TRANSFERENCE">A friendly Faction warlock can transfer damage to this model even if this model has a number of fury points equal to its current FURY.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SHIELD GUARD">Once per round, when a friendly model is directly hit by a ranged attack during your opponent's turn while within 2" of this model, you can choose to have this model directly hit instead. This model is automatically hit and suffers all damage and effects. This model cannot use Shield Guard if it is incorporeal, knocked down, or stationary.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB04" name="Nephilim Soldier" full_name="Nephilim Soldier" qualification="Legion Light Warbeast" fa="U" cost="5" fury="3" threshold="10" damage_spiral="8-7-7" completed="true">
          <basestats name="SOLDIER" spd="6" str="9" mat="6" rat="3" def="13" arm="16" cmd="8" eyelesssight="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Two-Handed Sword" pow="5" p_plus_s="14" reach="true" />
          </weapons>
          <animus name="MASSACRE" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Target friendly model can charge without being forced. When the affected model destroys an enemy model with a charge attack, after the attack is resolved it can advance up to 1" and make an additional melee attack. Massacre lasts for one turn.</animus>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB05" name="Raek" full_name="Raek" qualification="Legion Light Warbeast" fa="U" cost="4" fury="3" threshold="9" damage_spiral="6-7-7" completed="true">
          <basestats name="RAEK" spd="7" str="8" mat="6" rat="3" def="15" arm="14" cmd="6" eyelesssight="true" pathfinder="true" stealth="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Bite" pow="3" p_plus_s="11" location="H" />
            <melee_weapon name="Tail Strike" pow="4" p_plus_s="12" reach="true" />
          </weapons>
          <animus name="SHADOW SHIFT" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">This model gains Parry. Shadow Shift lasts for one turn. (A model with Parry cannot be targeted by free strikes.)</animus>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="BOUNDING LEAP">Once per activation, after making a full advance but before performing an action, this model can be forced to be placed completely within 5" of its current location. Any effects that prevent charging also prevent this model from using Bounding Leap.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB06" name="Teraph" full_name="Teraph" qualification="Legion Light Warbeast" fa="U" cost="5" fury="3" threshold="9" damage_spiral="6-7-7" completed="true">
          <basestats name="TERAPH" spd="6" str="8" mat="5" rat="6" def="13" arm="16" cmd="7" advance_deployment="true" eyelesssight="true" pathfinder="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Blight Blast" rng="10" rof="1" aoe="3" pow="13" location="H" fire="true" />
			<melee_weapon name="Tail Strike" pow="4" p_plus_s="12" reach="true" />            
          </weapons>
          <animus name="COUNTERBLAST" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">When an enemy model advances and ends its movement in this model's command range, this model can make one normal melee or ranged attack targeting that model, then Counterblast expires. Counterblast lasts for one round.</animus>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="DIG IN (★ACTION)">This model gains cover, does not suffer blast damage, and does not block LOS. This model remains dug in until it moves, is placed, or is engaged. This model cannot dig into solid rock or man-made constructions. This model can begin the game dug in.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB07" name="Seraph" full_name="Seraph" qualification="Legion Heavy Warbeast" fa="U" cost="8" fury="4" threshold="9" damage_spiral="8-9-8" completed="true">
          <basestats name="SERAPH" spd="6" str="10" mat="6" rat="5" def="14" arm="16" cmd="7" eyelesssight="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Blight Strike" rng="10" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="12" location="H" fire="true">
              <capacity title="STRAFE [D3+1] (★ATTACK)">Make d3+1 ranged attacks targeting a primary target and any number of secondary targets within 2" of the first target. Ignore intervening models when declaring secondary targets. A secondary target cannot be targeted by more attacks than the primary target. Strafe counts as one attack for ROF.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
			<melee_weapon name="Stinger" pow="4" p_plus_s="14">
              <capacity title="CRITICAL POISON">On a critical hit, gain an additional die on this weapon's damage rolls against living models.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>            
          </weapons>
          <animus name="SLIPSTREAM" cost="1" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">When this model ends its normal movement, one friendly Faction model this model moved within 2" of is placed completely within 2" of the friendly Faction model's current location, then Slipstream expires. A model can be placed by Slipstream only once per turn. Slipstream lasts for one turn.</animus>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SERPENTINE">This model cannot make slam or trample power attacks and cannot be knocked down.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB08" name="Angelius" full_name="Angelius" qualification="Legion Heavy Warbeast" fa="U" cost="9" fury="4" threshold="9" damage_spiral="8-9-8" completed="true">
          <basestats name="ANGELIUS" spd="7" str="10" mat="6" rat="5" def="14" arm="17" cmd="7" eyelesssight="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Flame Jet" rng="12" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="12" location="H" fire="true" critical_fire="true" />
			<melee_weapon name="Tail Strike" pow="4" p_plus_s="14" reach="true">
              <capacity title="ARMOR PIERCING (★ATTACK)">When calculating damage from this attack, halve the base ARM stats of models hit that have medium or larger bases. This attack gains +2 to damage rolls against models with small bases.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>            
          </weapons>
          <animus name="REPULSION" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Enemy models currently within 2" of this model are immediately pushed 3" directly away from it in the order you choose.</animus>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="OVERTAKE">When this model destroys one or more enemy warrior models with a normal melee attack, after the attack is resolved this model can immediately advance up to 1".</capacity>
          <capacity title="SERPENTINE">This model cannot make slam or trample power attacks and cannot be knocked down.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB09" name="Carnivean" full_name="Carnivean" qualification="Legion Heavy Warbeast" fa="U" cost="11" fury="4" threshold="9" damage_spiral="8-12-10" completed="true">
          <basestats name="CARNIVEAN" spd="6" str="12" mat="6" rat="4" def="11" arm="18" cmd="7" eyelesssight="true" pathfinder="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Dragon Breath" rng="SP10" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="14" location="H" fire="true" />
			<melee_weapon name="Bite" pow="6" p_plus_s="18" location="H" />
            <melee_weapon name="Talon" pow="4" p_plus_s="16" open_fist="true" location="L" />
            <melee_weapon name="Talon" pow="4" p_plus_s="16" open_fist="true" location="R" />            
          </weapons>
          <animus name="SPINY GROWTH" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Target friendly Faction model gains +2 ARM. If a warjack or warbeast hits the affected model with a melee attack, the attacking model suffers d3 damage points immediately after the attack has been resolved unless the affected model was destroyed or removed from play by the attack. Spiny Growth lasts for one round.</animus>
          <capacity title="ASSAULT">As part of a charge, after moving but before making its charge attack, this model can make one ranged attack targeting the model charged unless they were in melee with each other at the start of this model's activation. When resolving an Assault ranged attack, the attacking model does not suffer the target in melee penalty. If the target is not in melee range after moving, this model can make the Assault ranged attack before its activation ends.</capacity>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB10" name="Typhon" full_name="Typhon" qualification="Legion Character Heavy Warbeast" fa="C" cost="12" fury="4" threshold="9" damage_spiral="10-10-10" completed="true">
          <basestats name="TYPHON" spd="6" str="11" mat="7" rat="5" def="13" arm="17" cmd="7" eyelesssight="true" gunfighter="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Blight Breath" rng="SP8" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="14" fire="true" />
			<melee_weapon name="Bite" pow="6" p_plus_s="17">
              <capacity title="CRITICAL PITCH">On a critical hit, instead of rolling damage normally you can choose to have this model throw the model hit. Treat the throw as if this model had hit with and passed the STR check of a throw power attack. The thrown model suffers a damage roll with POW equal to this model's STR plus the POW of the weapon. The POW of collateral damage is equal to this model's STR.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>            
          </weapons>
          <animus name="EXCESSIVE HEALING" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">When this model is damaged by an enemy attack, immediately after resolving the attack this model heals d3 damage points. Excessive Healing lasts for one round.</animus>
          <capacity title="AFFINITY [THAGROSH]">When Typhon is forced to use Regenerate in Thagrosh's control area, instead of rolling to determine how many damage points Typhon heals, Typhon and Thagrosh each heal up to 3 damage points.</capacity>
          <capacity title="CIRCULAR VISION">This model's front arc extends to 360 degrees.</capacity>
          <capacity title="MULTIPLE HEADS">This model can make three initial attacks each combat action, using any combination of Blight Breath and Bite attacks. This model loses one initial attack for each aspect it has lost. This model cannot be forced to make additional Blight Breath attacks.</capacity>
          <capacity title="REGENERATION [D3]">This model can be forced to heal d3 damage points once per activation. This model cannot use Regeneration during an activation it runs.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB11" name="Scythean" full_name="Scythean" qualification="Legion Heavy Warbeast" fa="U" cost="9" fury="4" threshold="9" damage_spiral="8-12-10" completed="true">
          <basestats name="SCYTHEAN" spd="6" str="12" mat="6" rat="4" def="11" arm="18" cmd="7" eyelesssight="true" pathfinder="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Scythe" pow="5" p_plus_s="17" reach="true" location="L">
              <capacity title="CHAIN ATTACK: BLOODBATH">If this model hits the same target with both its initial attacks with this weapon, after resolving the attacks it can immediately make one melee attack with this weapon against each model in its LOS that is in this weapon's melee range.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
            <melee_weapon name="Scythe" pow="5" p_plus_s="17" reach="true" location="R">
              <capacity title="CHAIN ATTACK: BLOODBATH">See above.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <animus name="SLAUGHTERHOUSE" cost="1" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">This model gains Take Down. Slaughterhouse lasts for one turn. (Models disabled by a melee attack made by a model with Take Down cannot make a Tough roll. Models boxed by a melee attack made by this model are removed from play.)</animus>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB12" name="Stinger" full_name="Stinger" qualification="Legion Lesser Warbeast" fa="U" cost="2" fury="2" threshold="7" damage_spiral="4-4-5" completed="true">
          <basestats name="STINGER" spd="6" str="6" mat="5" rat="4" def="13" arm="12" cmd="7" eyelesssight="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Flame Spitter" rng="SP6" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="10" location="H" fire="true" />
			<melee_weapon name="Barbed Stinger" pow="6" p_plus_s="12" reach="true">
              <capacity title="POISON">Gain an additional die on this weapon's damage rolls against living models.</capacity>
              <capacity title="SUICIDAL ATTACK">If this weapon damages a model, immediately after the attack is resolved, mark all the damage circles in this warbeast's body aspect.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>            
          </weapons>
          <animus name="LURKER" cost="1" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Target friendly model gains Bushwhack. Lurker lasts for one turn. (During its activation, a model with Bushwhack can make its combat action before its normal movement. If it does, it must make a full advance as its normal movement this activation.)</animus>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="LESSER WARBEAST">This model cannot make power attacks.</capacity>
          <capacity title="DIG IN (★ACTION)">This model gains cover, does not suffer blast damage, and does not block LOS. This model remains dug in until it moves, is placed, or is engaged. This model cannot dig into solid rock or man-made constructions. This model can begin the game dug in.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB13" name="Ravagore" full_name="Ravagore" qualification="Legion Heavy Warbeast" fa="U" cost="10" fury="4" threshold="9" damage_spiral="8-12-10" completed="true">
          <basestats name="RAVAGORE" spd="6" str="12" mat="5" rat="5" def="11" arm="18" cmd="7" eyelesssight="true" pathfinder="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Blight Blast" rng="14" rof="1" aoe="3" pow="15" location="H" fire="true" corrosion="true">
              <capacity title="SCATHER">This attack's AOE remains in play for one round. Enemy models and non-Faction friendly models entering or ending their activations in the AOE suffer 1 point of corrosion damage.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
			<melee_weapon name="Talon" pow="4" p_plus_s="16" open_fist="true" location="L" />
            <melee_weapon name="Talon" pow="4" p_plus_s="16" open_fist="true" location="R" />            
          </weapons>
          <animus name="DRAGON'S FIRE" cost="1" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Target friendly Faction warbeast's ranged weapons gain Continuous Effect: Fire. Dragon's Fire lasts for one turn.</animus>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB14" name="Nephilim Bolt Thrower" full_name="Nephilim Bolt Thrower" qualification="Legion Light Warbeast" fa="U" cost="6" fury="3" threshold="10" damage_spiral="8-7-7" completed="true">
          <basestats name="BOLT THROWER" spd="6" str="9" mat="5" rat="5" def="13" arm="16" cmd="8" eyelesssight="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Ballista" rng="12" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="14">
              <capacity title="THUNDERBOLT">Enemy models hit are pushed d3" directly away from the attacking model. On a critical hit, the enemy model is knocked down after being pushed.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
			<melee_weapon name="Bow Blade" pow="3" p_plus_s="12" />            
          </weapons>
          <animus name="GLIDER" cost="1" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">This model gains Flight. Glider lasts for one turn. (A model with Flight can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty, can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them, and ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.)</animus>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB15" name="Proteus" full_name="Proteus" qualification="Legion Character Heavy Warbeast" fa="C" cost="11" fury="5" threshold="9" damage_spiral="8-12-10" completed="true">
          <basestats name="PROTEUS" spd="6" str="12" mat="6" rat="6" def="11" arm="18" cmd="7" eyelesssight="true" pathfinder="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Tentacle Lash" rng="6" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="14" location="H" chain="true">
              <capacity title="CHAIN WEAPON">This attack ignores the Buckler and Shield weapon qualities and Shield Wall.</capacity>
              <capacity title="DRAG">If this weapon damages an enemy model with an equal or smaller base, immediately after the attack is resolved the damaged model can be pushed any distance directly toward this model. After the damaged model is moved, this model can make one normal melee attack against the model pushed. After resolving this melee attack, this model can make additional melee attacks during its combat action.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
			<melee_weapon name="Tentacles" pow="2" p_plus_s="14" reach="true" location="H" chain="true">
              <capacity title="CHAIN WEAPON">See above.</capacity>
              <capacity title="PULL">If this weapon hits an enemy model with an equal or smaller base, immediately after the attack is resolved the hit model can be pushed any distance directly toward this model.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
            <melee_weapon name="Talon" pow="4" p_plus_s="16" open_fist="true" location="L" />
            <melee_weapon name="Talon" pow="4" p_plus_s="16" open_fist="true" location="R" />            
          </weapons>
          <animus name="HEIGHTENED METABOLISM" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Target friendly warbeast gains Snacking. Heightened Metabolism lasts for one turn. (When a model with Snacking boxes a living model with a melee attack, the model with Snacking can heal d3 damage points. If the model heals, the boxed model is removed from play.)</animus>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="HERDING">While this model is in its warlock's control area, the warlock can force, leach, reave, heal, and transfer damage to the warbeasts in its battlegroup that are in this model's command range.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SPECIAL ISSUE [ABSYLONIA]">This model can be included in Absylonia's theme forces. It can also be bonded to Absylonia.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB16" name="Naga Nightlurker" full_name="Naga Nightlurker" qualification="Legion Light Warbeast" fa="U" cost="5" fury="3" threshold="8" damage_spiral="7-5-7" completed="true">
          <basestats name="NAGA" spd="6" str="8" mat="5" rat="6" def="13" arm="15" cmd="6" eyelesssight="true" pathfinder="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Night's Venom" rng="10" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="12" magical="true" location="H">
              <capacity title="CRITICAL POISON">On a critical hit, gain an additional die on this weapon's damage rolls against living models.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
			<melee_weapon name="Bite" pow="4" p_plus_s="12" location="H">
              <capacity title="CRITICAL SHADOW BIND">On a critical hit, the model hit suffers Shadow Bind for one round. (A model suffering Shadow Bind suffers –3 DEF, and for one round when it advances it cannot move except to change facing.)</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>            
          </weapons>
          <animus name="WRAITHBANE" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Target friendly Faction model's weapons gain Magical Weapon and Blessed. Wraithbane lasts for one turn. (When making an attack with a weapon with Blessed, ignore spell effects that add to a model's ARM or DEF.)</animus>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="PROWL">This model gains Stealth while within terrain that provides concealment, the AOE of a spell that provides concealment, or the AOE of a cloud effect.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SERPENTINE">This model cannot make slam or trample power attacks and cannot be knocked down.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB17" name="Archangel" full_name="Archangel" qualification="Legion Gargantuan" fa="2" cost="20" fury="4" threshold="9" damage_spiral="13-18-15" completed="true">
          <basestats name="ARCHANGEL" spd="6" str="14" mat="6" rat="5" def="11" arm="18" cmd="7" eyelesssight="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Dragon Breath" rng="10" rof="1" aoe="3" pow="14" location="H" fire="true" critical_fire="true">
              <capacity title="STRAFE [D3+1] (★ATTACK)">Make d3+1 ranged attacks targeting a primary target and any number of secondary targets within 2" of the first target. Ignore intervening models when declaring secondary targets. A secondary target cannot be targeted by more attacks than the primary target. Strafe counts as one attack for ROF.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
			<melee_weapon name="Bite" pow="5" p_plus_s="19" location="H">
              <capacity title="CONSUME">If the attack hit a small-based non-warlock/warcaster model the model hit is removed from play.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
            <melee_weapon name="Claws" pow="3" p_plus_s="17" open_fist="true" location="L" />
            <melee_weapon name="Claws" pow="3" p_plus_s="17" open_fist="true" location="R" />            
          </weapons>
          <animus name="DRACONIC AURA" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">This model gains Righteous Flames. Draconic Aura lasts for one round. (An enemy model that ends its activation within 2" of a model with Righteous Flames suffers the Fire continuous effect.)</animus>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="RIDE-BY ATTACK">This model can make ride-by attacks.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB18" name="Nephilim Bloodseer" full_name="Nephilim Bloodseer" qualification="Legion Light Warbeast" fa="U" cost="5" fury="3" threshold="10" damage_spiral="8-6-8" completed="true">
          <basestats name="BLOODSEER" spd="6" str="8" mat="5" rat="3" def="12" arm="18" cmd="8" eyelesssight="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Gaff" pow="4" p_plus_s="12" reach="true">
              <capacity title="BRUTAL CHARGE">The model gains +2 to charge attack damage rolls with this weapon.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <animus name="WITCH BLIGHT" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">When an enemy model casts a spell while within 5" of this model, increase the COST by 1. Enemy models cannot upkeep spells on models within 5" of this model. Witch Blight lasts for one round.</animus>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="PRIMAL MAGIC">This model can use the animus of any friendly Faction non-character warbeast in its command range as if the animus were its own.</capacity>
          <capacity title="TELEMETRY">Other friendly Faction models gain +2 to magic attack rolls against enemy models within 5" of this model.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB19" name="Afflictor" full_name="Afflictor" qualification="Legion Light Warbeast" fa="U" cost="4" fury="3" threshold="9" damage_spiral="6-5-7" completed="true">
          <basestats name="AFFLICTOR" spd="6" str="7" mat="6" rat="4" def="13" arm="15" cmd="7" eyelesssight="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Ovipositor" pow="5" p_plus_s="12" reach="true">
              <capacity title="INFECTION">Once per activation, when this model boxes a living enemy warrior model with an attack with this weapon, remove the boxed model from play and replace it with an Incubus model.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <animus name="COERCED PROTECTOR" cost="1" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">This model gains Sacrificial Pawn [Soulless Warrior] for one round. (When a model with Sacrificial Pawn [Soulless Warrior] is directly hit by an enemy ranged attack, you can choose to have one friendly, non-incorporeal soulless warrior model within 3" of the model directly hit instead. That model is automatically hit and suffers all damage and effects.)</animus>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="INSCRUTABLE">Opponents cannot take control of this model.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB20" name="Belphagor" full_name="Belphagor" qualification="Legion Character Light Warbeast" fa="C" cost="0" fury="3" threshold="9" damage_spiral="6-6-12" completed="true">
          <basestats name="BELPHAGOR" spd="5" str="9" mat="6" rat="4" def="12" arm="19" cmd="6" eyelesssight="true" immunity_corrosion="true" immunity_electricity="true" immunity_fire="true" immunity_frost="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Claw" pow="4" p_plus_s="13" open_fist="true" location="L" />
            <melee_weapon name="Claw" pow="4" p_plus_s="13" open_fist="true" location="R" />
          </weapons>
          <animus name="DESPOILER" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Center a 5" AOE cloud effect on this model. The AOE remains centered on the model. Enemy models entering or ending their activations in the AOE suffer 1 damage point. Despoiler lasts for one round.</animus>
          <capacity title="COMPANION [BETHAYNE, VOICE OF EVERBLIGHT]">This model is included in any army that includes Bethayne, Voice of Everblight. If Bethayne is destroyed or removed from play, remove this model from play. This model is part of Bethayne's battlegroup.</capacity>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="CHANNELER [BETHAYNE]">While this model is not engaged and is in Bethayne's control area, she can channel spells through it.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
          <restricted_to id="EW07" />
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB21" name="Neraph" full_name="Neraph" qualification="Legion Heavy Warbeast" fa="U" cost="7" fury="4" threshold="9" damage_spiral="8-9-8" completed="true">
          <basestats name="NERAPH" spd="6" str="10" mat="6" rat="5" def="14" arm="16" cmd="7" eyelesssight="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Grasping Tail" pow="4" p_plus_s="14" location="-">
              <capacity title="COIL">When this model directly hits a model with this weapon, its melee attacks against that model automatically hit for one turn.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
            <melee_weapon name="Hammerhead" pow="6" p_plus_s="16" location="H" />
          </weapons>
          <animus name="VORTEX" cost="1" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Enemy models currently within 2" of this model are immediately pushed 2" directly toward it in the order you choose.</animus>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SERPENTINE">This model cannot make slam or trample power attacks and cannot be knocked down.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
        </warbeast>
        <warbeast id="EB22" name="Blight Wasps" full_name="Blight Wasps" qualification="Legion Warbeast Pack" fa="U" cost="4" fury="0" threshold="8" completed="true" isWarbeastPack="true" nbModelsInPack="4">
          <basestats name="LEADER &amp; GRUNTS" spd="7" str="4" mat="5" rat="1" def="12" arm="11" cmd="4" eyeless_sight="true" hitpoints="5"  />
          <weapons>            
            <melee_weapon name="Stinger" pow="4" p_plus_s="8">
              <capacity title="CRITICAL POISON">On a critical hit, gain an additional die on this weapon's damage rolls against living models.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <animus name="OVERWHELM" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Models in target friendly warbeast pack gain Killing Spree for one turn. (When a model with Killing Spree destroys one or more enemy models with a melee attack during its combat action, after that attack is resolved the model can move up to 1" and make one additional melee attack.)</animus>
          <capacity title="ANNOYANCE">Living enemy models within 1" of this model suffer -1 to attack rolls.</capacity>
          <capacity title="BLOOD CREATION">This model never attacks friendly Faction warlocks and cannot choose them as its frenzy target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="HUNTING PACK">This model gains a +1 cumulative bonus to melee attack and damage rolls for each other model in this unit engaging the model it is attacking.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>     
        </warbeast>       
        <warbeast id="EB23" name="Zuriel" full_name="Zuriel" qualification="Legion Nephilim Character Heavy Warbeast" fa="C" cost="9" fury="4" threshold="10" damage_spiral="10-9-9" completed="true">
          <basestats name="ZURIEL" spd="6" str="11" mat="7" rat="5" def="12" arm="19" cmd="9" eyeless_sight="true" gunfighter="true" />
          <weapons>            
            <ranged_weapon name="Dragon Breath" rng="SP8" rof="2" aoe="-" pow="12" location="H" fire="true" continuous_fire="true" />
            <melee_weapon name="War Blade" pow="5" p_plus_s="16" location="L">
              <capacity title="CHAIN ATTACK: CHAR">If this model hits the same model with both its initial attacks with this weapon, after resolving the attacks it can immediately make one ranged attack targeting that model.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
            <melee_weapon name="War Blade" pow="5" p_plus_s="16" location="R">
              <capacity title="CHAIN ATTACK: CHAR">See above.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <animus name="PREDATOR'S INSTINCT" cost="1" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">This model gains an additional die on attack rolls against non-warcaster, non-warlock warrior models. Predator's Instinct lasts for one turn.</animus>
          <capacity title="AFFINITY [RHYAS]">While Zuriel is in Rhyas' control area, he gains Stealth.</capacity>
          <capacity title="AFFINITY [SAERYN]">While Zuriel is not engaged and is in Saeryn's control area, she can channel spells through him.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SPECIAL ISSUE [RHYAS OR SAERYN]">This model can be included in Rhyas' or Saeryn's theme forces. It can also be bonded to Rhyas or Saeryn.</capacity>
        </warbeast>        
      </warbeasts>
      <battleEngines>
        <battleEngine id="EE01" name="Throne of Everblight" full_name="Throne of Everblight" qualification="Legion Battle Engine" fa="2" cost="9" completed="true">
          <basestats name="THRONE OF EVERBLIGHT" spd="5" str="10" mat="7" rat="1" def="10" arm="19" cmd="10" hitpoints="24" fearless="true" immunity_frost="true" terror="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Tentacle" pow="5" count="3" p_plus_s="15" reach="true" chain="true">
              <capacity title="CHAIN STRIKE">This weapon has a 4" melee range during this model's activation.</capacity>
              <capacity title="CHAIN WEAPON">This attack ignores the Buckler and Shield weapon qualities and Shield Wall.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="BATTLE WIZARD">Once per turn, when this model destroys one or more enemy models with a melee attack during its activation, immediately after the attack is resolved it can make one Magic Ability special attack or special action.</capacity>
          <capacity title="CIRCULAR VISION">This model's front arc extends to 360 degrees.</capacity>
          <capacity title="THE FEEDING">When it destroys a living enemy model with a melee attack, remove the enemy model from play, and this model gains a corpse token. This model can have up to three corpse tokens at a time. During its activation, this model can spend corpse tokens to boost attack or damage rolls at one token per boost.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="GROSS ANATOMY">During its activation, this model can spend corpse tokens to heal damage. For each corpse token spent remove d3 damage from this model.</capacity>
          <capacity title="MAGIC ABILITY [7]" />
          <capacity title="● FROSTBITE (★ATTACK)">Frostbite is a RNG SP 8 magic attack. Models hit suffer a POW 12 cold damage roll.</capacity>
          <capacity title="● SPINE BURST (★ATTACK)">Spine Burst is a RNG 10, POW 10 magic attack. If target model is hit, d3 nearest models within 5" of it suffer a POW 10 magical damage roll.</capacity>
        </battleEngine>
      </battleEngines>
      <units>
        <unit id="EU01" name="Blighted Nyss Archers" full_name="Blighted Nyss Archers" qualification="Legion Unit" fa="2" base_cost="5" full_cost="8" baseCount="6" fullCount="10" has_unit_attachment="true" completed="true">
          <basestats name="LEADER &amp; GRUNTS" spd="6" str="4" mat="5" rat="5" def="13" arm="11" cmd="8" cra="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Nyss Longbow" rng="12" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="10" />
			<melee_weapon name="Sword" pow="3" p_plus_s="7" />            
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="SUPPRESSING FIRE (ORDER)">This order can be issued only if two or more models with ranged weapons in this unit in formation are able to forfeit their actions. Each model in this unit in formation must forfeit its action. Other than the Standard Bearer, those models that do are participants. After all models in this unit have completed their normal movement, place an AOE completely within 12" of all participants, with its center point in LOS of all participants, ignoring intervening models The size of the AOE is based on the number of participants. If there are 2–4, the AOE is 3". If there are 5–7, the AOE is 4". If there are 8 or more, the AOE is 5". When a model enters or ends its activation within the AOE, it suffers a POW 10 damage roll. Suppressing Fire lasts for one round or until all participants have been destroyed or removed from play.</capacity>
          <unit_attachment id="EA01" name="Blighted Nyss Archer Officer &amp; Ammo Porter" full_name="Blighted Nyss Archer Officer &amp; Ammo Porter" qualification="Legion Unit Attachment" fa="1" cost="2" completed="true">
            <model id="Blighted Nyss Archer Officer">
              <basestats name="OFFICER" spd="6" str="4" mat="6" rat="6" def="13" arm="11" cmd="9" hitpoints="5" cra="true" officer="true" />
              <weapons>
                <ranged_weapon name="Nyss Longbow" rng="12" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="10" />
				<melee_weapon name="Sword" pow="3" p_plus_s="7" />                
              </weapons>
              <capacity title="GRANTED: COMBINED ARMS">While this model is in play, models in its unit gain Combined Arms. (When a model with Combined Arms misses an attack roll for a combined ranged attack, it can reroll that attack roll. Each attack roll can be rerolled only once as a result of Combined Arms).</capacity>
              <capacity title="TACTICS: PATHFINDER">Models in this unit gain Pathfinder.</capacity>
            </model>
            <model id="Blighted Nyss Archer Ammo Porter">
              <basestats name="AMMO PORTER" spd="6" str="4" mat="6" rat="6" def="13" arm="11" cmd="8" />
              <weapons />
              <capacity title="READY AMMO">While this model is in formation, models in its unit gain Dual Shot and their ranged weapons become ROF 2. (When a model with Dual Shot forfeits its movement to gain the aiming bonus it can also make one additional ranged attack that activation.)</capacity>
              <capacity title="TAKE UP">If this model is destroyed or removed from play, you can choose a Grunt in this unit within 1" of this model to take its place. Effects on this model expire, and it gains the effects on the chosen Grunt. Remove the Grunt from the table instead of this model. This model has the same number of unmarked damage boxes as the chosen Grunt.</capacity>
            </model>
          </unit_attachment>
        </unit>
        <unit id="EU02" name="Blighted Nyss Legionnaires" full_name="Blighted Nyss Legionnaires" qualification="Legion Unit" fa="2" base_cost="4" full_cost="6" baseCount="6" fullCount="10" has_unit_attachment="true" completed="true">
          <basestats name="LEADER &amp; GRUNTS" spd="5" str="6" mat="6" rat="4" def="12" arm="14" cmd="9" fearless="true" cma="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Great Sword" pow="4" p_plus_s="10" reach="true" />
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="DEFENSIVE LINE">While this model is B2B with one or more models in its unit, it gains +2 ARM.</capacity>
          <capacity title="VENGEANCE">During your Maintenance Phase, if one or more models in this unit were destroyed or removed from play by enemy attacks during your opponent's last turn, each model in the unit can advance 3" and make one normal melee attack.</capacity>
          <unit_attachment id="EA05" name="Captain Farilor &amp; Standard" full_name="Captain Farilor &amp; Standard" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Legionnaire Character Unit Attachment" fa="C" cost="3" completed="true">
            <model id="Captain Farilor">
              <basestats name="FARILOR" spd="5" str="6" mat="7" rat="4" def="12" arm="14" cmd="9" hitpoints="5" fearless="true" cma="true" officer="true" />
              <weapons>
                <melee_weapon name="Great Sword" pow="4" p_plus_s="10" reach="true" weapon_master="true" />
              </weapons>
              <capacity title="CLEAVE">When this model destroys one or more enemy models with a melee attack during its activation, immediately after the attack is resolved the model can make one additional melee attack. This model can gain only one additional attack from Cleave each activation.</capacity>
              <capacity title="DEFENSIVE LINE">While this model is B2B with one or more models in its unit, it gains +2 ARM.</capacity>
              <capacity title="IRON ZEAL">Once per game during its unit's activation, this model can use Iron Zeal. For one round, while in formation models in this unit gain +4 ARM and cannot become stationary or be knocked down.</capacity>
              <capacity title="TACTICS: SET DEFENSE">Models in this unit gain Set Defense. (A model in the front arc of a model with Set Defense suffers –2 on charge, slam power attack, and impact attack rolls against the model with Set Defense.)</capacity>
              <capacity title="VENGEANCE">During your Maintenance Phase, if one or more models in this unit were destroyed or removed from play by enemy attacks during your opponent's last turn, each model in the unit can advance 3" and make one normal melee attack.</capacity>
            </model>
            <model id="Blighted Nyss Standard">
              <basestats name="STANDARD BEARER" spd="5" str="6" mat="6" rat="4" def="12" arm="14" cmd="9" hitpoints="0" fearless="true" standard_bearer="true" />
              <weapons />
              <capacity title="DEFENSIVE LINE">See above.</capacity>
              <capacity title="MAGE STATIC">While this model is in formation, enemy magic attacks targeting a model in this model's unit suffer –5 RNG.</capacity>
              <capacity title="VENGEANCE">See above.</capacity>
            </model>
          </unit_attachment>
        </unit>
        <unit id="EU03" name="Blighted Nyss Swordsmen" full_name="Blighted Nyss Swordsmen" qualification="Legion Unit" fa="2" base_cost="5" full_cost="8" baseCount="6" fullCount="10" has_unit_attachment="true" completed="true">
          <basestats name="LEADER &amp; GRUNTS" spd="6" str="7" mat="7" rat="4" def="14" arm="13" cmd="8" fearless="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Nyss Claymore" pow="4" p_plus_s="11" weapon_master="true" />
          </weapons>
          <unit_attachment id="EA02" name="Blighted Nyss Swordsmen Abbot &amp; Champion" full_name="Blighted Nyss Swordsmen Abbot &amp; Champion" qualification="Legion Unit Attachment" fa="1" cost="3" completed="true">
            <model id="Blighted Nyss Swordsman Abbot">
              <basestats name="ABBOT" spd="6" str="7" mat="8" rat="4" def="14" arm="13" cmd="9" hitpoints="5" fearless="true" officer="true" />
              <weapons>
                <melee_weapon name="Nyss Claymore" pow="4" p_plus_s="11" weapon_master="true" />
              </weapons>
              <capacity title="GRANTED: CLEAVE">While this model is in play, models in its unit gain Cleave. (When a model with Cleave destroys one or more enemy models with a melee attack during its activation, immediately after the attack is resolved the model can make one additional melee attack. A model can gain only one additional attack from Cleave per activation.)</capacity>
              <capacity title="TACTICS: OVERTAKE">Models in this unit gain Overtake. (When a model with Overtake destroys one or more enemy warrior models with a normal melee attack, after the attack is resolved this model can immediately advance up to 1".)</capacity>
            </model>
            <model id="Blighted Nyss Swordsman Champion">
              <basestats name="CHAMPION" spd="6" str="7" mat="8" rat="4" def="14" arm="13" cmd="8" hitpoints="5" fearless="true" />
              <weapons>
                <melee_weapon name="Nyss Claymore " pow="4" count="2" p_plus_s="11" weapon_master="true">
                  <capacity title="COMBO STRIKE (★ATTACK)">Make a melee attack. Instead of making a normal damage roll, the POW of the damage roll is equal to this model's STR plus twice the POW of this weapon.</capacity>
                </melee_weapon>
              </weapons>
              <capacity title="DEFENSIVE STRIKE">Once per turn, when an enemy model advances into and ends its movement in this model's melee range, this model can immediately make one normal melee attack against it.</capacity>
            </model>
          </unit_attachment>
        </unit>
        <unit id="EU04" name="Blighted Nyss Raptors" full_name="Blighted Nyss Raptors" qualification="Legion Light Cavalry Unit" fa="1" base_cost="6" full_cost="10" baseCount="3" fullCount="5" completed="true">
          <basestats name="LEADER &amp; GRUNTS" spd="9" str="6" mat="6" rat="7" def="14" arm="15" cmd="8" hitpoints="5" pathfinder="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Nyss Longbow" rng="12" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="10">
              <capacity title="POISON">Gain an additional die on this weapon's damage rolls against living models.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
			<melee_weapon name="Nyss Claymore" pow="4" p_plus_s="10" weapon_master="true" />            
            <mount_weapon name="Mount" pow="12" />
          </weapons>
        </unit>
        <unit id="EU05" name="Blighted Nyss Scather Crew" full_name="Blighted Nyss Scather Crew" qualification="Legion Weapon Crew Unit" fa="2" base_cost="3" full_cost="-" baseCount="3" fullCount="-" completed="true">
          <basestats name="LEADER" spd="4" str="4" mat="5" rat="5" def="13" arm="11" cmd="8" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Scather Catapult" rng="15" rof="1" aoe="3" pow="14" corrosion="true">
              <capacity title="ARCING FIRE"> When attacking with this weapon, this model can ignore intervening models except those within 1" of the target. </capacity>
              <capacity title="LIGHT ARTILLERY">This weapon cannot be used to make attacks or special actions during activations this model moves. This model cannot gain the aiming bonus when attacking with this weapon and cannot charge. If this model attacks with this weapon during its activation, it cannot attack with any other weapons that activation.</capacity>
              <capacity title="MINIMUM RANGE [6]">Attacks made with this weapon cannot target any model within 6" of it.</capacity>
              <capacity title="RANGE FINDER">While B2B with one or more Grunts in this unit, this model gains +2 to attack rolls with this weapon.</capacity>
              <capacity title="SCATHER">This attacks AOE remains in play for one round. Enemy models and non-Faction friendly models entering or ending their activations in the AOE suffer 1 point of corrosion damage.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
			<melee_weapon name="Sword" pow="3" p_plus_s="7" />            
          </weapons>
          <model id="scather_crew_grunt" full_name="Grunt" qualification="model">
            <basestats name="GRUNT" spd="4" str="4" mat="5" rat="5" def="13" arm="11" cmd="8" />
            <weapons>
              <melee_weapon name="Sword" pow="3" p_plus_s="7" />
            </weapons>
          </model>
        </unit>
        <unit id="EU06" name="Spawning Vessel" full_name="Spawning Vessel" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Unit" fa="1" base_cost="2" full_cost="3" baseCount="5" fullCount="7" completed="true">
          <basestats name="VESSEL" spd="0" str="0" mat="0" rat="0" def="5" arm="18" cmd="0" hitpoints="10" construct="true" />
          <weapons />
          <capacity title="CARRIED">This model is not a warrior model. It can advance only during its unit's normal movement. When it advances, it can move up to 1" for each Grunt in this unit within 2" of it at the beginning of this unit's activation. This model is automatically hit by melee attacks. It cannot be knocked down or made stationary.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FOCAL POINT">This model's unit has no unit commander. Models in this unit within 8" of this model are in formation. If a model in this model's unit is out of formation when beginning its normal movement, it must either advance toward this model and forfeit its action or run directly toward this model. If this model is destroyed or removed from play, remove the remaining models in this unit from play.</capacity>
          <capacity title="LAST CALL">If this model is disabled by an enemy attack, it can immediately make a special action.</capacity>
          <capacity title="RECYCLE">When a living model is destroyed within 4" of this model + 1" for each Grunt in this unit that is in formation, place one corpse token on this model. This model can have up to three corpse tokens at a time.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SPAWN HORROR (★ACTION)">Remove three corpse tokens from this model to place a non-character Faction lesser warbeast into play under your control. Place the warbeast within 3" of this model and choose a friendly Faction warlock. This warbeast becomes part of that warlock's battlegroup.</capacity>
          <model id="spawning_vessel_grunt" full_name="Grunt" qualification="model">
            <basestats name="GRUNT" spd="6" str="6" mat="5" rat="4" def="13" arm="11" cmd="8" />
            <weapons>
              <melee_weapon name="Gaff" pow="3" p_plus_s="9" reach="true" />
            </weapons>
            <capacity title="STONE HEART">This model never flees and automatically passes command checks.</capacity>
          </model>
        </unit>
        <unit id="EU07" name="Strider Rangers" full_name="Strider Rangers" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Unit" fa="2" base_cost="6" full_cost="-" baseCount="6" fullCount="-" has_unit_attachment="true" completed="true">
          <basestats name="LEADER &amp; GRUNTS" spd="7" str="6" mat="5" rat="6" def="15" arm="11" cmd="8" advance_deployment="true" cra="true" pathfinder="true" stealth="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Nyss Longbow" rng="12" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="10" />
			<melee_weapon name="Sword" pow="3" p_plus_s="9" />            
          </weapons>
          <unit_attachment id="EA03" name="Strider Rangers Officer &amp; Musician" full_name="Strider Rangers Officer &amp; Musician" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Unit Attachment" fa="1" cost="3" completed="true">
            <model id="Blighted Nyss Strider Officer">
              <basestats name="OFFICER" spd="7" str="6" mat="6" rat="7" def="15" arm="11" cmd="9" hitpoints="5" advance_deployment="true" cra="true" officer="true" pathfinder="true" stealth="true" />
              <weapons>
                <ranged_weapon name="Nyss Longbow" rng="12" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="10" />
				<melee_weapon name="Sword" pow="3" p_plus_s="9" />                
              </weapons>
              <capacity title="ATTACHMENT [STRIDER RANGERS]">This attachment can be added to a Strider Rangers unit.</capacity>
              <capacity title="GRANTED: REFORM">While this model is in play, after all models in its unit have completed their actions, each can advance up to 3".</capacity>
              <capacity title="TACTICS: HUNTER">Models in this unit gain Hunter. (A model with Hunter ignores forests, concealment, and cover when determining LOS or making a ranged attack.)</capacity>
            </model>
            <model id="Blighted Nyss Strider Musician">
              <basestats name="MUSICIAN" spd="7" str="6" mat="5" rat="6" def="15" arm="11" cmd="8" hitpoints="0" advance_deployment="true" cra="true" pathfinder="true" stealth="true" />
              <weapons>
                <ranged_weapon name="Nyss Longbow" rng="12" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="10" />
				<melee_weapon name="Sword" pow="3" p_plus_s="9" />                
              </weapons>
              <capacity title="IN STEP">While this model is within 3" of it, the unit commander gains +3" to its command range.</capacity>
              <capacity title="TAKE UP">If this model is destroyed or removed from play, you can choose a Grunt in this unit within 1" of this model to take its place. Effects on this model expire, and it gains the effects on the chosen Grunt. Remove the Grunt from the table instead of this model. This model has the same number of unmarked damage boxes as the chosen Grunt.</capacity>
            </model>
          </unit_attachment>
        </unit>
        <unit id="EU08" name="Blighted Ogrun Warmongers" full_name="Blighted Ogrun Warmongers" qualification="Legion Unit" fa="3" base_cost="5" full_cost="8" baseCount="3" fullCount="5" completed="true">
          <basestats name="LEADER &amp; GRUNTS" spd="5" str="9" mat="7" rat="3" def="12" arm="16" cmd="8" hitpoints="8" fearless="true" terror="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="War Cleaver" pow="5" p_plus_s="14" reach="true" />
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="BERSERK">When this model destroys one or more models with a melee attack during its combat action, immediately after the attack is resolved it must make one additional melee attack against another model in its melee range.</capacity>
        </unit>
        <unit id="EU09" name="Blighted Ogrun Warspears" full_name="Blighted Ogrun Warspears" qualification="Legion Unit" fa="3" base_cost="5" full_cost="8" baseCount="3" fullCount="5" has_unit_attachment="true" completed="true">
          <basestats name="LEADER &amp; GRUNTS" spd="5" str="9" mat="7" rat="5" def="12" arm="16" cmd="8" hitpoints="8" fearless="true" terror="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Thrown Spear" rng="8" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="4">
              <capacity title="THROWN">Add this model's STR to the POW of this ranged attack.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
			<melee_weapon name="War Spear" pow="4" p_plus_s="13" reach="true">
              <capacity title="SET DEFENSE">A model in this model's front arc suffers –2 on charge, slam power attack, and impact attack rolls against this model.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>            
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="ASSAULT (ORDER)">Affected models must charge or run. As part of a charge, after moving but before making its charge attack, an affected model can make one ranged attack targeting the model charged unless they were in melee with each other at the start of the affected model's activation. Models that received this order cannot make combined ranged attacks this activation. When resolving an Assault ranged attack, the attacking model does not suffer the target in melee penalty. If the target is not in melee range after moving, the affected model must still make the ranged attack before its activation ends.</capacity>
          <unit_attachment id="EA06" name="Warspear Chieftan" full_name="Warspear Chieftan" qualification="Legion Blighted Ogrun Unit Attachment" fa="2" cost="2" completed="true">
            <model id="Warspear Chieftan">
              <basestats name="CHIEFTAIN" spd="5" str="9" mat="8" rat="6" def="12" arm="16" cmd="9" hitpoints="8" fearless="true" officer="true" terror="true" />
              <weapons>
                <ranged_weapon name="Thrown Spear" rng="8" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="4">
                  <capacity title="THROWN">Add this model's STR to the POW of this ranged attack.</capacity>
                </ranged_weapon>
				<melee_weapon name="War Spear" pow="4" p_plus_s="13" reach="true">
                  <capacity title="SET DEFENSE">A model in this model's front arc suffers –2 on charge, slam power attack, and impact attack rolls against this model.</capacity>
                </melee_weapon>                
              </weapons>
              <capacity title="ATTACHMENT [BLIGHTED OGRUN WARSPEAR]">This attachment can be added to a Blighted Ogrun Warspear unit.</capacity>
              <capacity title="HUNTSMAN">After deployment but before the first player's turn, choose an enemy model/unit to be this unit's prey. While this model is in play, each model in its unit beginning its activation within 10" of the prey gains +2" movement that activation. While this model is in play, models in its unit gains +2 to attack and damage rolls against the prey. When the prey is destroyed or removed from play, choose another model/unit as the prey.</capacity>
              <capacity title="TACTICS: RELENTLESS CHARGE">Models in this unit gain Relentless Charge. (Models with Relentless Charge gain Pathfinder during activations they charge.)</capacity>
            </model>
          </unit_attachment>
        </unit>
        <unit id="EU10" name="Blighted Nyss Grotesques" full_name="Blighted Nyss Grotesques" qualification="Legion Unit" fa="2" base_cost="4" full_cost="6" baseCount="6" fullCount="10" completed="true">
          <basestats name="LEADER &amp; GRUNTS" spd="5" str="7" mat="5" rat="4" def="13" arm="13" cmd="6" fearless="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Claws" pow="3" p_plus_s="10" />
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="GANG">When making a melee attack targeting an enemy model in melee range of another model in this unit, this model gains +2 to melee attack and melee damage rolls.</capacity>
        </unit>
        <unit id="EU11" name="Blighted Nyss Hex Hunters" full_name="Blighted Nyss Hex Hunters" qualification="Legion Unit" fa="2" base_cost="5" full_cost="8" baseCount="6" fullCount="10" has_unit_attachment="true" completed="true">
          <basestats name="LEADER &amp; GRUNTS" spd="7" str="6" mat="7" rat="4" def="14" arm="12" cmd="8" pathfinder="true" stealth="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Hex Razor" pow="4" p_plus_s="10" magical="true" />
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="BATTLE WIZARD">Once per turn, when this model destroys one or more enemy models with a melee attack during its activation, immediately after the attack is resolved it can make one Magic Ability special attack or special action.</capacity>
          <capacity title="MAGIC ABILITY [6]" />
          <capacity title="● HEX BOLT (★ATTACK)">Hex Bolt is a RNG 6, POW 13 magic attack. Models hit cannot make special actions or special attacks for one round.</capacity>
          <unit_attachment id="EA04" name="Bayal, Hound of Everblight" full_name="Bayal, Hound of Everblight" qualification="Legion Character Unit Attachment" fa="C" cost="3" completed="true">
            <model id="Bayal, Hound of Everblight">
              <basestats name="BAYAL" spd="7" str="6" mat="8" rat="4" def="14" arm="12" cmd="9" hitpoints="5" officer="true" pathfinder="true" stealth="true" />
              <weapons>
                <melee_weapon name="Hex Razor" pow="4" count="2" p_plus_s="10" magical="true" weapon_master="true">
                  <capacity title="SHADOW BIND">A model hit by this weapon suffers –3 DEF and when it advances it cannot move except to change facing. Shadow Bind expires after one round.</capacity>
                </melee_weapon>
              </weapons>
              <capacity title="ATTACHMENT [HEX HUNTERS]">This attachment can be added to a Hex Hunters unit.</capacity>
              <capacity title="BATTLE WIZARD">Once per turn, when this model destroys one or more enemy models with a melee attack during its activation, immediately after the attack is resolved it can make one Magic Ability special attack or special action.</capacity>
              <capacity title="GRANTED: HUNTER">While this model is in play, models in this unit gain Hunter. (A model with Hunter ignores forests, concealment, and cover when determining LOS or making a ranged attack.)</capacity>
              <capacity title="MAGIC ABILITY [7]" />
              <capacity title="● FROSTBITE (★ATTACK)">Frostbite is a RNG SP 8 magic attack. Models hit suffer a POW 12 cold damage roll.</capacity>
              <capacity title="● HEX BOLT (★ATTACK)">Hex Bolt is a RNG 6, POW 13 magic attack. Models hit cannot make special actions or special attacks for one round.</capacity>
              <capacity title="TACTICS: ADVANCE DEPLOYMENT">Models in this unit gain Advance Deployment.</capacity>
            </model>
          </unit_attachment>
        </unit>
        <unit id="EU12" name="Blackfrost Shard" full_name="Blackfrost Shard" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Character Unit" fa="C" base_cost="5" full_cost="-" baseCount="3" fullCount="-" completed="true">
          <basestats name="SEVRYN" spd="6" str="5" mat="7" rat="4" def="14" arm="12" cmd="9" hitpoints="5" immunity_frost="true" officer="true" pathfinder="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Nyss Claymore" pow="4" p_plus_s="9" magical="true" weapon_master="true" />
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="MAGIC ABILITY [7]" />
          <capacity title="● DISBINDING (★ACTION)">Enemy upkeep spells on this model and/or its unit immediately expire.</capacity>
          <capacity title="● ICE BOLT (★ATTACK)">Ice Bolt is a RNG 10 magic attack. A model hit suffers a POW 12 cold damage roll. On a critical hit, the model hit becomes stationary for one round unless it has Immunity: Cold.</capacity>
          <capacity title="● ICE CAGE (★ATTACK)">Ice Cage is a RNG 10 magic attack. A model hit suffers a cumulative –2 DEF for one turn unless it has Immunity: Cold. When a model without Immunity: Cold is hit with three or more Ice Cage attacks the same turn, it becomes stationary for one round.</capacity>
          <model id="Rhylyss" full_name="Rhylyss" qualification="model">
            <basestats name="RHYLYSS" spd="6" str="5" mat="7" rat="4" def="14" arm="12" cmd="9" hitpoints="5" immunity_frost="true" pathfinder="true" />
            <weapons>
              <melee_weapon name="Nyss Claymore" pow="4" p_plus_s="9" magical="true" weapon_master="true" />
            </weapons>
            <capacity title="MAGIC ABILITY [7]" />
            <capacity title="● ICE BOLT (★ATTACK)">See above.</capacity>
            <capacity title="● ICE CAGE (★ATTACK)">See above.</capacity>
            <capacity title="● KISS OF LYLISS (★ATTACK)">Kiss of Lyliss is a RNG 10 magic attack. For one round, when a model/unit hit by Kiss of Lyliss suffers a damage roll add +2 to the roll.</capacity>
          </model>
          <model id="Vysarr" full_name="Vysarr" qualification="model">
            <basestats name="VYSARR" spd="6" str="5" mat="7" rat="4" def="14" arm="12" cmd="9" hitpoints="5" immunity_frost="true" pathfinder="true" />
            <weapons>
              <melee_weapon name="Nyss Claymore" pow="4" p_plus_s="9" magical="true" weapon_master="true" />
            </weapons>
            <capacity title="MAGIC ABILITY [7]" />
            <capacity title="● ICE BOLT (★ATTACK)">See above.</capacity>
            <capacity title="● ICE CAGE (★ATTACK)">See above.</capacity>
            <capacity title="● CLOAK OF MIST (★ACTION)">While in formation models in this unit gain Stealth. Cloak of Mist lasts for one round.</capacity>
          </model>
        </unit>
        <unit id="EU13" name="Strider Blightblades" full_name="Strider Blightblades" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Unit" fa="2" base_cost="6" full_cost="-" baseCount="6" fullCount="-" completed="true">
          <basestats name="LEADER &amp; GRUNTS" spd="7" str="6" mat="6" rat="5" def="15" arm="11" cmd="8" cma="true" pathfinder="true" stealth="true" />
          <weapons>            
            <melee_weapon name="Blade" count="2" pow="3" p_plus_s="9">
              <capacity title="CRITICAL GRIEVOUS WOUNDS">On a critical hit, the model hit by this weapon loses Tough, cannot heal or be healed, and cannot transfer damage for one round.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="AMBUSH">You can choose not to deploy this unit at the start of the game. If it is not deployed normally, you can put it into play at the end of any of your Control Phases after your first turn. When you do, choose any table edge except the back of your opponent's deployment zone. Place all models in this unit in formation within 3" of the chosen table edge.</capacity>          
        </unit>        
      </units>
      <solos>
        <solo id="ES01" name="Blighted Nyss Sorceress &amp; Hellion" full_name="Blighted Nyss Sorceress &amp; Hellion" qualification="Legion Cavalry Solo" fa="2" cost="4" completed="true">
          <basestats name="SORCERESS" spd="8" str="5" mat="6" rat="4" def="14" arm="16" cmd="8" hitpoints="10" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Spear" pow="4" p_plus_s="9" magical="true" reach="true" />
            <mount_weapon name="Mount" pow="10" />
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="AERIAL COORDINATION">Friendly Faction warbeasts with Flight beginning their activations in this model's command range can charge without being forced.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FLIGHT">This model can advance through terrain and obstacles without penalty and can advance through obstructions and other models if it has enough movement to move completely past them. This model ignores intervening models when declaring its charge target.</capacity>
          <capacity title="MAGIC ABILITY [7]" />
          <capacity title="● BLIGHT STORM (★ACTION)">Place a 5" AOE anywhere completely in this model's command range. When an enemy model in the AOE is directly hit by an attack and the damage roll fails to exceed its ARM, it automatically suffers 1 damage point. Blight Storm lasts for one round.</capacity>
          <capacity title="● FROSTBITE (★ATTACK)">Frostbite is a RNG SP 8 magic attack. Models hit suffer a POW 12 cold damage roll.</capacity>
          <capacity title="● WIND RAVAGER (★ACTION)">While in this model's command range, enemy models cannot make ranged attacks for one round.</capacity>
        </solo>
        <solo id="ES02" name="Incubus" full_name="Incubus" qualification="Legion Solo" fa="2" cost="5" completed="true">
          <basestats name="INCUBUS" spd="6" str="8" mat="7" rat="3" def="12" arm="15" cmd="6" fearless="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Claws " pow="3" count="2" p_plus_s="11">
              <capacity title="COMBO STRIKE (★ATTACK)">Make a melee attack. Instead of making a normal damage roll, the POW of the damage roll is equal to this model's STR plus twice the POW of this weapon.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="HOST">Incubi models do not begin the game in play. When a friendly living non-Incubus, non-warlock, small-based Faction warrior model is destroyed, you can mark its center point and remove that model from play. You can only mark up to one point for each Incubus you have that has not been put into play or removed from play. During your next Maintenance Phase, put one Incubus model into play within 2" of each point marked. If there is not room to place an Incubus model, remove the marker from the table and remove from play one Incubi that has not been put into play.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
        </solo>
        <solo id="ES03" name="Blighted Nyss Shepherd" full_name="Blighted Nyss Shepherd" qualification="Legion Solo" fa="2" cost="1" completed="true">
          <basestats name="SHEPHERD" spd="6" str="5" mat="5" rat="4" def="14" arm="12" cmd="8" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Crooked Staff" pow="4" p_plus_s="9" reach="true" />
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="BEAST MANIPULATION">A warbeast can be affected by only one Beast Manipulation special action each turn.</capacity>
          <capacity title="● CONDITION (★ACTION)">RNG 3. Target friendly Faction warbeast. If the warbeast is in range, place any number of fury points on or remove any number of fury points from it.</capacity>
          <capacity title="● MEDICATE (★ACTION)">RNG 3. Target friendly Faction warbeast. If the warbeast is in range, it heals d3 damage points. A warbeast can be affected by Medicate only once per turn.</capacity>
          <capacity title="BEAST MASTER">This model can force friendly Faction warbeasts in its command range as if it were their controlling warlock.</capacity>
        </solo>
        <solo id="ES04" name="Strider Deathstalker" full_name="Strider Deathstalker" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Solo" fa="2" cost="2" completed="true">
          <basestats name="DEATHSTALKER" spd="7" str="6" mat="7" rat="8" def="15" arm="11" cmd="9" hitpoints="5" advance_deployment="true" pathfinder="true" stealth="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Nyss Longbow" rng="12" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="10" />
			<melee_weapon name="Sword" pow="3" p_plus_s="9" />            
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="LEADERSHIP [STRIDERS]">While in this model's command range, friendly Strider models gain Swift Hunter.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SNAP FIRE">When this model destroys one or more enemy models with a ranged attack during its combat action, immediately after that attack is resolved this model can make one normal ranged attack. Attacks gained from Snap Fire do not count against a weapon's ROF and cannot generate additional attacks from Snap Fire.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SNIPER">When damaging a warjack or warbeast with a ranged attack, choose which column or branch suffers damage. Instead of rolling damage on a ranged attack, this model can inflict 1 damage point. A model that participates in a combined ranged attack loses Sniper until the attack is resolved.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SWIFT HUNTER">When this model destroys an enemy model with a normal ranged attack, immediately after the attack is resolved it can advance up to 2".</capacity>
        </solo>
        <solo id="ES05" name="The Forsaken" full_name="The Forsaken" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Solo" fa="2" cost="2" completed="true">
          <basestats name="FORSAKEN" spd="6" str="7" mat="5" rat="4" def="14" arm="14" cmd="8" hitpoints="5" abomination="true" fearless="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Claw" pow="5" p_plus_s="12" />
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="BLIGHT SHROUD (★ACTION)">Remove all fury points from this model. Enemy models within 1" of this model for each fury point removed suffer a POW 8 damage roll. Add an additional die to the damage roll for each focus or fury point on the enemy model.</capacity>
          <capacity title="CONSUME FURY">RNG CMD. Target friendly Faction warbeast. If the warbeast is in range, remove up to 5 fury points from it and put them on this model. This model can have up to 5 fury points at a time.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FEROCIOUS">During its activation, this model can spend fury points to gain additional attacks or to boost attack or damage rolls, at 1 fury point per attack or boost.</capacity>
        </solo>
        <solo id="ES06" name="Warmonger War Chief" full_name="Warmonger War Chief" qualification="Legion Blighted Ogrun Solo" fa="2" cost="3" completed="true">
          <basestats name="WAR CHIEF" spd="5" str="9" mat="8" rat="3" def="12" arm="17" cmd="9" hitpoints="8" fearless="true" terror="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="War Cleaver" pow="5" p_plus_s="14" reach="true" />
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="BERSERK">When this model destroys one or more models with a melee attack during its combat action, immediately after the attack is resolved it must make one additional melee attack against another model in its melee range.</capacity>
          <capacity title="BLOOD DRINKER">Immediately after this model resolves a melee attack in which it destroys one or more living models, it can end its activation to heal d3 damage points.</capacity>
          <capacity title="LEADERSHIP [BLIGHTED OGRUN]">While in this model's command range, friendly Blighted Ogrun models gain Blood Drinker.</capacity>
          <capacity title="VETERAN LEADER [BLIGHTED OGRUN]">Friendly Blighted Ogrun trooper models gain +2 to attack rolls while this model is in their LOS.</capacity>
        </solo>
        <solo id="ES07" name="Spell Martyr" full_name="Spell Martyr" qualification="Legion Solo" fa="3" cost="1" completed="true">
          <basestats name="SPELL MARTYR" spd="6" str="5" mat="4" rat="1" def="13" arm="12" cmd="6" fearless="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Claws" pow="3" p_plus_s="8" />
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="SOULLESS">This model does not generate a soul token when it is destroyed.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SPIRITUAL CONFLAGRATION">While this model is not in melee and is in a friendly Faction warlock's control area, the warlock can channel a spell through it. Remove this model from play after the spell is cast.</capacity>
        </solo>
        <solo id="ES08" name="Annyssa Ryvaal, Talon of Everblight" full_name="Annyssa Ryvaal, Talon of Everblight" qualification="Blighted Nyss Light Cavalry Character Solo" fa="C" cost="4" completed="true">
          <basestats name="RYVAAL" spd="9" str="6" mat="6" rat="7" def="15" arm="15" cmd="9" hitpoints="8" pathfinder="true" stealth="true" />
          <weapons>
            <ranged_weapon name="Nyss Longbow" rng="12" rof="1" aoe="-" pow="10">
              <capacity title="POISON">Gain an additional die on this weapon's damage rolls against living models.</capacity>
            </ranged_weapon>
            <mount_weapon name="Mount" pow="12" />
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="PARRY">This model cannot be targeted by free strikes.</capacity>
          <capacity title="PREY">After deployment but before the first player's turn, choose an enemy model/unit to be this model/unit's prey. This model gains +2 to attack and damage rolls against its prey. When this model begins its activation within 10" of its prey, it gains +2" movement that activation. When the prey is destroyed or removed from play, choose another model/unit to be the prey.</capacity>
          <capacity title="SNAP FIRE">When this model destroys one or more enemy models with a ranged attack during its combat action, immediately after that attack is resolved this model can make one normal ranged attack. Attacks gained from Snap Fire do not count against a weapon's ROF and cannot generate additional attacks from Snap Fire.</capacity>
          <capacity title="VETERAN LEADER [RAPTOR]">Friendly Raptor trooper models gain +2 to attack rolls while this model is in their LOS.</capacity>
        </solo>
        <solo id="ES09" name="Succubus" full_name="Succubus" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Solo" fa="1" cost="2" warcaster_attachment="true" completed="true">
          <basestats name="SUCCUBUS" spd="6" str="4" mat="4" rat="3" def="14" arm="11" cmd="6" hitpoints="5" />
          <weapons />
          <capacity title="ATTACHED">Before the start of the game, attach this model to a friendly Faction warlock for the rest of the game. Each warlock can have only one model attached to it.</capacity>
          <capacity title="ARCANE ASSIST">If its warlock is in this model's command range during your Control Phase, the warlock can upkeep one spell without spending fury.</capacity>
          <capacity title="MAGIC ABILITY [6]" />
          <capacity title="● SPIRIT TAP (★ACTION)">This model immediately casts the animus of a friendly Faction warbeast in its command range as a spell. This model cannot cast an animus with a RNG of SELF. This model must make a special attack to cast an offensive spell. Other spells are cast by making a special action.</capacity>
        </solo>
        <solo id="ES10" name="Beast Mistress" full_name="Beast Mistress" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Solo" fa="2" cost="3" completed="true">
          <basestats name="BEAST MISTRESS" spd="6" str="5" mat="5" rat="4" def="14" arm="13" cmd="9" hitpoints="5" fearless="true" lesser_warlock="true" focus="4" pathfinder="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Nyss Claymore" pow="4" p_plus_s="9" />
          </weapons>
		  <spell name="BLOOD RAIN" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="3" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES">Blood Rain causes corrosion damage. Models hit suffer the Corrosion continuous effect.</spell>
		  <spell name="ENERGIZER" cost="*" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">This model spends up to 3 fury points to cast Energizer. Models in its battlegroup that are currently in its control area can immediately advance up to 1" for each fury point spent. Energizer can be cast only once per turn.</spell>
          <capacity title="DRACONIC CONSORT">This model is not a warlock but has the following warlock special rules: Battlegroup Commander, Control Area, Damage Transference, Forcing, Fury Manipulation, Healing, and Spellcaster. This model can have only non-character Faction lesser warbeasts in its battlegroup.</capacity>
          <capacity title="FIELD MARSHAL [AGGRESSIVE]">Models in this model's battlegroup gain Aggressive. (A model with Aggressive can run or charge without spending focus or being forced.)</capacity>
          <capacity title="FLANK [LESSER WARBEAST]">When this model makes a melee attack against an enemy model within the melee range of a friendly model of the type indicated, this model gains +2 to attack rolls and gains an additional damage die.</capacity>
          <restricted_to id="EB01"/>
          <restricted_to id="EB02"/>
          <restricted_to id="EB12"/>
        </solo>
        <solo id="ES11" name="Fyanna the Lash" full_name="Fyanna the Lash" qualification="Legion Blighted Nyss Character Solo" fa="C" cost="3" completed="true">
          <basestats name="FYANNA" spd="7" str="7" mat="7" rat="4" def="15" arm="12" cmd="9" hitpoints="5" pathfinder="true" />
          <weapons>
            <melee_weapon name="Barbed Lash" pow="5" p_plus_s="12" reach="true" chain="true">
              <capacity title="CHAIN STRIKE">This weapon has a 4" melee range during this model's activation. </capacity>
              <capacity title="CHAIN WEAPON">This attack ignores the Buckler and Shield weapon qualities and Shield Wall.</capacity>
            </melee_weapon>
          </weapons>
          <capacity title="ATTACK TYPE">Each time this model makes a normal melee attack, choose one of the following abilities:</capacity>
          <capacity title="● DISMEMBER">When this model hits a warbeast with a melee attack, roll an additional damage die.</capacity>
          <capacity title="● PITCH">Instead of making a normal damage roll on a hit, this model can throw the model hit as if it had hit with and passed the STR check of a throw power attack. The thrown model suffers a damage roll with POW equal to this model's STR plus the POW of this weapon. The POW of collateral damage is equal to this model's STR.</capacity>
          <capacity title="● BEAT BACK">Immediately after a normal attack with this weapon is resolved during this model's combat action, the enemy model hit can be pushed 1" directly away from the attacking model. After the enemy model is pushed, the attacking model can advance up to 1".</capacity>
          <capacity title="EVASIVE">This model cannot be targeted by free strikes. This model can advance up to 2" immediately after an enemy ranged attack that missed it is resolved unless it was missed while advancing.</capacity>
          <capacity title="PROWL">This model gains Stealth while within terrain that provides concealment, the AOE of a spell that provides concealment, or the AOE of a cloud effect.</capacity>
          <capacity title="RAPID STRIKE">This model can make one additional melee attack each combat action.</capacity>
        </solo>
      </solos>
    </army>
  </armies>
</ruleset>
